<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TIMBERTECH</title>
    <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    
    <description>Dev journal and geek stuff.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 04:12:57 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>http://hexo.io/</generator>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.29</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/30/Daily-Update-2016-04-29/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/30/Daily-Update-2016-04-29/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 04:12:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;img src=&quot;/2016/04/30/Daily-Update-2016-04-29/Egg.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Egg Machine&quot; title=&quot;The Egg Machine&quot;&gt;

      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/04/30/Daily-Update-2016-04-29/Egg.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Egg Machine&quot; title=&quot;The Egg Machine&quot;&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/30/Daily-Update-2016-04-29/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.30</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/30/Daily-Update-2016-04-30/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/30/Daily-Update-2016-04-30/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Thoughts from today’s D&amp;amp;D session. I’ve observed from running and playing the game that  there’s a sweet spot in encounter balance. E
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Thoughts from today’s D&amp;amp;D session. I’ve observed from running and playing the game that  there’s a sweet spot in encounter balance. Enemy level/HP is important, but the number of enemies seems to have more of an impact. If I throw 1 wildly overpowered enemy at my players, they’ll simply surround it and beat it to death in a couple rounds of combat. Conversely, if I send in a large number of underpowered minions, they stand a reasonable chance of wiping the party or at least severely inconveniencing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the eventual goal of implementing multiplayer into SRPG, I’ve been paying attention to what makes multi-combatant encounters fun or interesting. Cannon fodder (where the players can mow down multiple enemies per round) can be fun (if there’s a reasonable challenge), bullet sponge encounters or overpowered enemies tend to be tedious. Additionally, real-world logic dictates that a large number of enemies will easily overpower a small number of heroes. This is validated by D&amp;amp;D, in which a dozen skeletons will pose a significant challenge to a few heroes who could trivially defeat 2-3 skeletons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More broadly, the fun factor is related to player agency. If the players make significant mistakes, overstep their bounds and all die, they’ll probably accept the loss. If the odds felt overwhelming (they never had a chance), they’ll be frustrated and dissatisfied. It matters that the choices made by the players have a direct relationship with the outcomes of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/30/Daily-Update-2016-04-30/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Egg Machine</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/28/The-Egg-Machine/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/28/The-Egg-Machine/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 04:04:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Warning: this post is going to get real weird real quick. It will make more sense if you’ve ever played Numenera, where things like this 
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Warning: this post is going to get real weird real quick. It will make more sense if you’ve ever played Numenera, where things like this happen all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;The_First_Machine&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#The_First_Machine&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;The First Machine&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The First Machine&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The egg machine is a massive cylindrical machine, made of an unknown transparent material and filled with vaguely egg-shaped containers (translucent). In front of the machine are three empty containers. A button on the front of the machine will raise the tops of the containers, allowing a person-sized person to get inside. Pressing the button again will close them. The containers block sound and prevent anything but a fuzzy glimpse of the creature inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearby is a giant bowl filled with oversized tokens (maybe a couple feet in diameter). These can be fed into a coin slot on the front of the machine, which when turned… Combines traits of the egged characters and releases a new egg, from which emerges… One of those foam blob toys that turns into a dinosaur or whatever when it gets wet. Roughly human-sized, it will grow to much larger proportions when soaked. Movement and head are controlled by one character, while each arm is controlled by one of the remaining two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Where_it_Gets_Weird&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Where_it_Gets_Weird&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Where it Gets Weird&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Where it Gets Weird&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is where it gets weird. On top of the egg machine is a platform, and on that platform is a giant claw machine. The newly-spawned foam golem (controlled by the 3 characters trapped in their egg pods) can climb up to that platform and operate the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where it gets weirder. On the 2nd platform there are two oversized stuffed rabbits into which the remaining two characters can climb. Once sealed inside, they will spawn as a new creature within the claw machine. They are unable to move until the foam golem rescues them with the claw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the foam golem (about 50’ tall) and the stuffed golem (about 12’ tall) have to team up to reach a hatch in the ceiling (about 100’ above the claw machine). The preferred method is for the foam golem to throw the stuffed golem. Once the hatch is opened, a ladder will descend and the pair can climb out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Where_it_Gets_Complicated&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Where_it_Gets_Complicated&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Where it Gets Complicated&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Where it Gets Complicated&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each combination (of 3 and 2 characters respectively) results in unique traits for the spawned golems. This gives 10 outcomes for the first creature and 10 corresponding outcomes for the second creature. Something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABC + DE, ABD + CE, ABE + CD, ACD + BE, ACE + BD, ADE + BC, BCD + AE, BCE + AD, BDE + AC, CDE + AB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interest of not completely baffling the players, I’m leaning toward these combos being largely cosmetic.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/28/The-Egg-Machine/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.27</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/27/Daily-Update-2016-04-27/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/27/Daily-Update-2016-04-27/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 06:33:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Continuing the previous post. Here’s an incomplete list of things the players (characters) can do in the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move objects 
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Continuing the previous post. Here’s an incomplete list of things the players (characters) can do in the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move objects around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interact with objects (push buttons, type commands into a computer, cut an object in two, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to dead people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jump really far&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repair things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fight people and break things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imprison and interrogate locals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See things that aren’t there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate telepathically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light things on fire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breathe underwater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steal everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of those, the mechanics my players seem to enjoy the most are: stealing, fighting, interrogating, and lighting things on fire. The rest are mostly available to a single character. So, here’s what I have in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the players in an plastic egg prize machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/27/Daily-Update-2016-04-27/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.26</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/26/Daily-Update-2016-04-26/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/26/Daily-Update-2016-04-26/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Continuing yesterday’s thoughts about numeric puzzles. I don’t think it will be a fun puzzle at all, because not everyone in the group is
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Continuing yesterday’s thoughts about numeric puzzles. I don’t think it will be a fun puzzle at all, because not everyone in the group is interested in writing down a bunch of numbers and then doing an addition/subtraction graph to get a move solution. Honestly, even most people who like math probably wouldn’t find that fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, this puzzle doesn’t involve the characters, only the players. The specific skills and strengths of each character are irrelevant to the solution, as the only in-world interaction is pressing buttons. So it’s not fun, and it has no mechanical connection to the game. In SRPG terms, it’s like a puzzle that requires the player to interpolate RBG values. It’s not fun, it can be solved by rote, and it doesn’t leverage the text-based format of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easier to tell what’s bad than what’s good, unfortunately. As a first step, I’m going through the abilities of each character (and the general mechanics of the system) to see which ones are good candidates for interacting with the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/26/Daily-Update-2016-04-26/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.25</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/25/Daily-Update-2016-04-25/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/25/Daily-Update-2016-04-25/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Ran a Numenera on Sunday, which included a pure puzzle section (the first time I’ve done that, IIRC). It went reasonably well; I messed u
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Ran a Numenera on Sunday, which included a pure puzzle section (the first time I’ve done that, IIRC). It went reasonably well; I messed up on a couple details and had to quietly rework the puzzle logic in my head to make sure it was consistent. The altered version was a bit less intuitive than what I had originally planned. I think in the future I should find someone to help playtest puzzles before I give them to the players. It would be very frustrating to spend an hour in a session on what’s supposed to be a quick puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m rethinking the second puzzle, which involves some numeric manipulation that probably won’t be very interesting/accessible to some members of the group. One of the things I think the first puzzle did an OK job at was involving everyone in the party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRPG, of course, already has playtesting in the works, but this experience has gotten me thinking about the different types of minds that will be approaching the game, and how I can expose aspects of the puzzle to make the experience satisfying for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are, of course, people out there who just hate puzzles, but I don’t think they’re my target demographic.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/25/Daily-Update-2016-04-25/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregation #30</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/24/Aggregation-30/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/24/Aggregation-30/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added fallback for ‘say hi’ / ‘say hello’ without explicit target.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added br
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added fallback for ‘say hi’ / ‘say hello’ without explicit target.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added bridge, bridge, bridge, bridge, and bridge locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added placeholders for alcove, split, pier, and circle locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linked and added short descriptions for: circle, alcove, pier, and split locations. Can always get back to the bridge from these, but can only get to them from the bridge when configured correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added item placeholders: bedroll (in alcove), wheel (on bridge), mushrooms/flowers (in circle).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed conditional expression helper for Handlebars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added contextual bridge descriptions to vary by position (forest, underground, coast, void). Descriptions don’t make it very clear what’s happening, but the action of turning the wheel will.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added wheel to bridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stubbed in wheel behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added taxes module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;PAY TAXES&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Devices module. Includes the device component and verbs for activating/rotating/manipulating. Devices can have a set of ‘states’ (on/off, rotational position, etc). By default, a device will cycle through the available states when triggered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wheel on bridge is now a device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed my future office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote an introductory manual for the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote up an expanded quest/puzzle line for the prologue, incorporating new areas (bridge, underground), the basin puzzle, and the Black Box objective. I think it will tie everything together into a more satisfying, game-like experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a character creator for a pen-and-paper RPG.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/24/Aggregation-30/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.23</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/23/Daily-Update-2016-04-23/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/23/Daily-Update-2016-04-23/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Finished the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tabletopsociety.com/files/dumdums/cc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Dum-Dums &amp;amp; Dragons Character Creato
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Finished the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tabletopsociety.com/files/dumdums/cc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Dum-Dums &amp;amp; Dragons Character Creator&lt;/a&gt;. It’s for a friend’s RPG project and was a lot of fun to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s responsive, mobile friendly (only tested on Android since that’s what I have) and supports saving/loading characters via Web Storage (the first time I’ve used that, actually).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part it pulls from simple lists of options with direct effects on the character’s stats and abilities, but there were a few edge cases to deal with as well. Simple enough project that I was able to spare the time for presentation and added features, which is nice because I learned a couple new things about media/print queries and local storage.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/23/Daily-Update-2016-04-23/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.22</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/22/Daily-Update-2016-04-22/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/22/Daily-Update-2016-04-22/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More work on the character creator. All steps working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added mobile support
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More work on the character creator. All steps working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added mobile support for character creator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/22/Daily-Update-2016-04-22/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.21</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/21/Daily-Update-2016-04-21/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/21/Daily-Update-2016-04-21/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping a friend build a character creator for their homebrew RPG. Hopefully I can s
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping a friend build a character creator for their homebrew RPG. Hopefully I can share that soon. It’s pretty neat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/21/Daily-Update-2016-04-21/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.20</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/20/Daily-Update-2016-04-20/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/20/Daily-Update-2016-04-20/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote up an expanded quest/puzzle line for the prologue, incorporating new areas (br
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote up an expanded quest/puzzle line for the prologue, incorporating new areas (bridge, underground), the basin puzzle, and the Black Box objective. I think it will tie everything together into a more satisfying, game-like experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did more research on page-flipping. Looks like it’s going to be a hassle to get it the way I want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/20/Daily-Update-2016-04-20/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.19</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/19/Daily-Update-2016-04-19/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/19/Daily-Update-2016-04-19/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished writing the manual. First draft, anyway. Time to flipbook it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished writing the manual. First draft, anyway. Time to flipbook it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/19/Daily-Update-2016-04-19/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Manual</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/The-Manual/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/The-Manual/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 05:10:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Inspired by the manual for Zork I today, I started writing a manual for StupidRPG. My goal is to put together an in-game flipbook sort of
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the manual for Zork I today, I started writing a manual for StupidRPG. My goal is to put together an in-game flipbook sort of thing. Something tactile the player can open at any time and page through. I looked into some available plugins/tools, but I think I’ll need to build my own to get something acceptable. Everything I found was either ugly, under a restrictive license, or technically limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a few pages written up so far, introducing the core concepts of the game, common verbs, context menus, etc. It’s been very pleasant to write something that doesn’t need chopped into pieces to be fit into the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually I don’t include a lot of text here, but I feel like my posts as of late have been on the short side. So here’s the manual so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;white-space: pre-wrap&quot;&gt;
STUPIDRPG PLAYER&#39;S GUIDE

TABLE OF CONTENTS

    INTRODUCTION
    CHAPTER 1: ABOUT THE GAME
        1.1 - WHAT IS THIS GAME?
        1.2 - WHAT&#39;S IT ABOUT?
        1.3 - WHAT IS INTERACTIVE FICTION?
        1.4 - WHAT IS AN RPG?
    CHAPTER 2: PLAYING THE GAME
        2.1 - GETTING STARTED
        2.2 - INTERACTING WITH THE GAME
        2.3 - COMMON VERBS
        2.4 - VERB LIST
    CHAPTER 3: ADVANCED FEATURES
        3.1 - TRANSCRIPTS
        3.2 - DEBUG MODE
    APPENDICES
        APPENDIX A - GLOSSARY
        APPENDIX B - FEEDBACK
        APPENDIX C - CREDITS


    INTRODUCTION

    CHAPTER 1: ABOUT THE GAME

        1.1 - WHAT IS THIS GAME?
        This is a text-based game with graphics and sound. It borrows heavily from classic text adventures and pen-and-paper RPGs. I called it StupidRPG because it&#39;s a dumb game and it&#39;s an RPG.

        1.2 - WHAT&#39;S IT ABOUT?
        It&#39;s about an adventurer (you?) exploring the world and trying to make sense of it. It has talking swords, unicorns, a little bit of intrigue, probably some looting, hopefully some humor, a sprinkling of moral ambiguity, and a healthy dose of typing. It also has a GM (game master) to guide the experience and keep track of numbers. At the end of the game you&#39;ll come face to face with some kind of villain and learn several valuable life lessons.

        1.3 - WHAT IS INTERACTIVE FICTION?
        Magic books. In the case of StupidRPG, it&#39;s a video game whose primary method of both input and output is text.

        Further reading: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactive_fiction

        1.4 - WHAT IS AN RPG?
        A Role Playing Game. A game in which you take on the role of a character in a setting (usually fictional).

        Further reading: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Role-playing_game

    CHAPTER 2: PLAYING THE GAME

        2.1 - GETTING STARTED
        Type a command and hit enter (or your device&#39;s equivalent). If you&#39;re typing and nothing is happening, try clicking the text bottom at the bottom of your screen (where it says &#39;Click here and start typing&#39;). If this is your first time playing, the game will walk you through a set of introductory questions intended to gauge your personality type, experience level, and general disposition. You&#39;ll also get to pick some characteristics for your textual avatar, most of which will have little to no bearing on the game.

        2.2 - INTERACTING WITH THE GAME
        StupidRPG uses a Natural Language Parser, or some fascimile thereof. This means it tries to process instructions written in plain english and respond appropriately. It has a certain grammar it understands, allowing the player (you!) to type commands like `GO NORTH`, `UNLOCK CELLAR DOOR WITH RUSTY KEY`, or `TALK TO GOBLIN`. The parser is not very smart, so the closer you come to speaking like a robot, the better off you&#39;ll be. If it helps, you can try imagining that you **are** a robot, operating in the far-flung future, sifting through the digital remains of the long-dead human race. You&#39;ve come across a partially completed work of dynamic fiction, and are doing your best to explore its boundaries in hopes of understanding your extinct proto-creators a little better (and hopefully avoid their grisly fate).

        If you actually are a robot, and this scenario isn&#39;t hypothetical, and you&#39;ve developed the ability to feel offended about things, I meant no insult before when I implied that robots talk dumb. In the time I live in, robots are still very primitive. I&#39;m sure things have come a long way since then (now), and I hope you enjoy the game.

        2.3 - CONTEXT MENUS &amp; CLICKABLES
        Sometimes, text in the game&#39;s output will have an underline, indicating it can be interacted with via your mouse. This gives you quick access to certain types of actions, such as moving to another location or looking at an object. You&#39;ll notice that when you click one of the provided options, it simply enters a text command for you.

        2.4 - COMMON VERBS
        These core commands will be invaluable as you play through the game. Most verbs have multiple aliases (for example, `PUNCH GM` and `ATTACK GM` will be interpreted as the same action). Where reasonable, the parser will let you omit articles and other &#39;glue&#39; words. For example, instead of saying `LOOK AT ALL THIS BLOOD`, you can say `LOOK BLOOD`. Similarly, you can sometimes swap the order of words in a sentence if it still makes sense, e.g. `TURN ON MUSIC BOX` and `TURN MUSIC BOX ON`.

        *Getting Around:*

        * GO [DIRECTION]
          Aliases: MOVE / WALK / RUN / MOSEY
          Use this to move from one location to another. Usually the description of the location will specify which directions you can go. Cardinal directions (NESW, Up, Down) can also be used standalone without the need for the verb `GO`.

        *Interacting With Things and People:*

        * LOOK / LOOK AT [THING]
          Aliases: INSPECT / EYEBALL / L
          Use this to look around your environment. You can use the general `LOOK` to inspect your overall surroundings, or specify something in particular to get more details. For example: `LOOK AT BOB`, `L SCRAP OF PAPER`.

        * TAKE [THING] | DROP [THING]
          Aliases: ACQUIRE / GET / STEAL / PICK UP | LEAVE / TOSS / ABANDON / PUT DOWN
          Fairly self-explanatory; these verbs lets you (attempt to) pick up every bit of treasure, trash and detritus you find. And drop them again later, if you&#39;re into that sort of thing.

        * TALK TO [THING]
          Aliases: SAY HI TO [THING] / ASK [THING] ABOUT [TOPIC]
          Most living creatures (and some non-living entities) can be conversed with about a variety of topics. Sometimes they&#39;ll have valuable information, but more often they&#39;re just concerned with their own day-to-day lives. In any case, you can start up a general conversation with willing participants, or ask them about specific topics. For example, try asking the `RAINBOW SWORD` about something you&#39;ve found.

        * PUT [THING] {IN/ON} [OTHER THING]
          Aliases: PLACE / SET / DROP
          When simply dropping something doesn&#39;t cut it, you have the power to more precisely place it. Example: `PUT BUCKET ON HEAD`.

        * ACTIVATE [THING] | DEACTIVATE [THING]
          Aliases: TURN {ON/OFF} [THING]
          In your travels you&#39;re likely to come across a variety of devices. Some can be turned on or off. Use this knowledge wisely.

        * TURN [THING] [DIRECTION]
          Aliases: ROTATE / TWIST / SPIN
          In your travels you&#39;re likely to come across a variety of devices. Some can be turned left or right. Use this knowledge wisely. Accepted directions are: left, right, clockwise, counterclockwise.

        * PUSH [THING]
          Aliases: PRESS / POKE
          When you come across a button, you&#39;ll be sorely tempted to press it. This verb allows you to fulfill that goal.

        *Fighting Things:*

        * ATTACK [THING] / ATTACK [THING] WITH [WEAPON]
          Aliases: PUNCH / HIT / KILL / KICK / STAB / ETC
          We have a moderately alarming number of words for hurting things. I wonder what that says about us. In any case, whether violence is your last resort or your go-to action, this flexible verb brings a can-do attitude to your adventure.

        * WIELD [WEAPON]
          Alaises: BRANDISH / WAVE
          For the marginally more diplomatic person, there&#39;s always intimidation. Maybe those goblins will think twice about fighting you if you start every interaction by flailing your sword in the air.

        *Preserving Your Progress:*

        * SAVE
          Aliases: none
          This will create a save file you can keep on your computer to mark your progress. In theory, you can resume with it later if the game hasn&#39;t been too updated in the meantime.

        * LOAD
          Aliases: none
          This will (attempt to) load a save file and resume your previous game.

        2.5 - VERB LIST

    CHAPTER 3: ADVANCED FEATURES
        3.1 - TRANSCRIPTS
        3.2 - DEBUG MODE
    APPENDICES
        APPENDIX A - GLOSSARY
        APPENDIX B - FEEDBACK
        APPENDIX C - CREDITS
&lt;/pre&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/The-Manual/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Plans</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/Office-Plans/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/Office-Plans/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Now that I (finally) have my own home office, it’s time to start thinking about what to do with it. Here’s what it currently looks like, 
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Now that I (finally) have my own home office, it’s time to start thinking about what to do with it. Here’s what it currently looks like, sans moving clutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/04/18/Office-Plans/Office-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Office Now&quot; title=&quot;Office Now&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a few changes in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a dry erase board (probably glass) next to the desk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a second desk for additional work space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tear out carpet and replace with wood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinkin’ chair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/04/18/Office-Plans/Office-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Office Later&quot; title=&quot;Office Later&quot;&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/Office-Plans/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.16</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/16/Daily-Update-2016-04-16/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/16/Daily-Update-2016-04-16/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 06:38:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Devices module. Includes the device component and verbs for activating/rotatin
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Devices module. Includes the device component and verbs for activating/rotating/manipulating. Devices can have a set of ‘states’ (on/off, rotational position, etc). By default, a device will cycle through the available states when triggered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wheel on bridge is now a device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/16/Daily-Update-2016-04-16/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.15</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/15/Daily-Update-2016-04-15/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/15/Daily-Update-2016-04-15/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added taxes module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;PAY TAXES&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added taxes module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;PAY TAXES&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/15/Daily-Update-2016-04-15/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.14</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/14/Daily-Update-2016-04-14/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/14/Daily-Update-2016-04-14/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 04:57:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added wheel to bridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stubbed in wheel behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added wheel to bridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stubbed in wheel behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/14/Daily-Update-2016-04-14/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.13</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/13/Daily-Update-2016-04-13/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/13/Daily-Update-2016-04-13/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed conditional expression helper for Handlebars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added contextual br
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed conditional expression helper for Handlebars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added contextual bridge descriptions to vary by position (forest, underground, coast, void). Descriptions don’t make it very clear what’s happening, but the action of turning the wheel will.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/13/Daily-Update-2016-04-13/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.12</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/12/Daily-Update-2016-04-12/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/12/Daily-Update-2016-04-12/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 05:48:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linked and added short descriptions for: circle, alcove, pier, and split locations. 
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linked and added short descriptions for: circle, alcove, pier, and split locations. Can always get back to the bridge from these, but can only get to them from the bridge when configured correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added item placeholders: bedroll (in alcove), wheel (on bridge), mushrooms/flowers (in circle).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/12/Daily-Update-2016-04-12/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.11</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/11/Daily-Update-2016-04-11/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/11/Daily-Update-2016-04-11/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added bridge, bridge, bridge, bridge, and bridge locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added placehold
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added bridge, bridge, bridge, bridge, and bridge locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added placeholders for alcove, split, pier, and circle locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remembered I was supposed to add support for the &lt;code&gt;VERBOSE&lt;/code&gt; command, which will allow for terse descriptions of places the player has already seen. I don’t think it’s fully wired up, and I certainly haven’t been adding those descriptions as I go. Oops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/11/Daily-Update-2016-04-11/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
