<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TIMBERTECH</title>
    <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    
    <description>Dev journal and geek stuff.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 23:28:02 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>http://hexo.io/</generator>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregation #30</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/24/Aggregation-30/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/24/Aggregation-30/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added fallback for ‘say hi’ / ‘say hello’ without explicit target.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added br
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added fallback for ‘say hi’ / ‘say hello’ without explicit target.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added bridge, bridge, bridge, bridge, and bridge locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added placeholders for alcove, split, pier, and circle locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linked and added short descriptions for: circle, alcove, pier, and split locations. Can always get back to the bridge from these, but can only get to them from the bridge when configured correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added item placeholders: bedroll (in alcove), wheel (on bridge), mushrooms/flowers (in circle).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed conditional expression helper for Handlebars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added contextual bridge descriptions to vary by position (forest, underground, coast, void). Descriptions don’t make it very clear what’s happening, but the action of turning the wheel will.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added wheel to bridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stubbed in wheel behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added taxes module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;PAY TAXES&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Devices module. Includes the device component and verbs for activating/rotating/manipulating. Devices can have a set of ‘states’ (on/off, rotational position, etc). By default, a device will cycle through the available states when triggered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wheel on bridge is now a device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed my future office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote an introductory manual for the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote up an expanded quest/puzzle line for the prologue, incorporating new areas (bridge, underground), the basin puzzle, and the Black Box objective. I think it will tie everything together into a more satisfying, game-like experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a character creator for a pen-and-paper RPG.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/24/Aggregation-30/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.23</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/23/Daily-Update-2016-04-23/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/23/Daily-Update-2016-04-23/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Finished the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tabletopsociety.com/files/dumdums/cc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Dum-Dums &amp;amp; Dragons Character Creato
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Finished the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tabletopsociety.com/files/dumdums/cc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Dum-Dums &amp;amp; Dragons Character Creator&lt;/a&gt;. It’s for a friend’s RPG project and was a lot of fun to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s responsive, mobile friendly (only tested on Android since that’s what I have) and supports saving/loading characters via Web Storage (the first time I’ve used that, actually).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part it pulls from simple lists of options with direct effects on the character’s stats and abilities, but there were a few edge cases to deal with as well. Simple enough project that I was able to spare the time for presentation and added features, which is nice because I learned a couple new things about media/print queries and local storage.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/23/Daily-Update-2016-04-23/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.22</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/22/Daily-Update-2016-04-22/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/22/Daily-Update-2016-04-22/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More work on the character creator. All steps working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added mobile support
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More work on the character creator. All steps working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added mobile support for character creator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/22/Daily-Update-2016-04-22/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.21</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/21/Daily-Update-2016-04-21/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/21/Daily-Update-2016-04-21/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping a friend build a character creator for their homebrew RPG. Hopefully I can s
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping a friend build a character creator for their homebrew RPG. Hopefully I can share that soon. It’s pretty neat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/21/Daily-Update-2016-04-21/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.20</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/20/Daily-Update-2016-04-20/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/20/Daily-Update-2016-04-20/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote up an expanded quest/puzzle line for the prologue, incorporating new areas (br
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote up an expanded quest/puzzle line for the prologue, incorporating new areas (bridge, underground), the basin puzzle, and the Black Box objective. I think it will tie everything together into a more satisfying, game-like experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did more research on page-flipping. Looks like it’s going to be a hassle to get it the way I want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/20/Daily-Update-2016-04-20/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.19</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/19/Daily-Update-2016-04-19/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/19/Daily-Update-2016-04-19/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished writing the manual. First draft, anyway. Time to flipbook it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished writing the manual. First draft, anyway. Time to flipbook it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/19/Daily-Update-2016-04-19/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Manual</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/The-Manual/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/The-Manual/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 05:10:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Inspired by the manual for Zork I today, I started writing a manual for StupidRPG. My goal is to put together an in-game flipbook sort of
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the manual for Zork I today, I started writing a manual for StupidRPG. My goal is to put together an in-game flipbook sort of thing. Something tactile the player can open at any time and page through. I looked into some available plugins/tools, but I think I’ll need to build my own to get something acceptable. Everything I found was either ugly, under a restrictive license, or technically limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a few pages written up so far, introducing the core concepts of the game, common verbs, context menus, etc. It’s been very pleasant to write something that doesn’t need chopped into pieces to be fit into the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually I don’t include a lot of text here, but I feel like my posts as of late have been on the short side. So here’s the manual so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;white-space: pre-wrap&quot;&gt;
STUPIDRPG PLAYER&#39;S GUIDE

TABLE OF CONTENTS

    INTRODUCTION
    CHAPTER 1: ABOUT THE GAME
        1.1 - WHAT IS THIS GAME?
        1.2 - WHAT&#39;S IT ABOUT?
        1.3 - WHAT IS INTERACTIVE FICTION?
        1.4 - WHAT IS AN RPG?
    CHAPTER 2: PLAYING THE GAME
        2.1 - GETTING STARTED
        2.2 - INTERACTING WITH THE GAME
        2.3 - COMMON VERBS
        2.4 - VERB LIST
    CHAPTER 3: ADVANCED FEATURES
        3.1 - TRANSCRIPTS
        3.2 - DEBUG MODE
    APPENDICES
        APPENDIX A - GLOSSARY
        APPENDIX B - FEEDBACK
        APPENDIX C - CREDITS


    INTRODUCTION

    CHAPTER 1: ABOUT THE GAME

        1.1 - WHAT IS THIS GAME?
        This is a text-based game with graphics and sound. It borrows heavily from classic text adventures and pen-and-paper RPGs. I called it StupidRPG because it&#39;s a dumb game and it&#39;s an RPG.

        1.2 - WHAT&#39;S IT ABOUT?
        It&#39;s about an adventurer (you?) exploring the world and trying to make sense of it. It has talking swords, unicorns, a little bit of intrigue, probably some looting, hopefully some humor, a sprinkling of moral ambiguity, and a healthy dose of typing. It also has a GM (game master) to guide the experience and keep track of numbers. At the end of the game you&#39;ll come face to face with some kind of villain and learn several valuable life lessons.

        1.3 - WHAT IS INTERACTIVE FICTION?
        Magic books. In the case of StupidRPG, it&#39;s a video game whose primary method of both input and output is text.

        Further reading: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactive_fiction

        1.4 - WHAT IS AN RPG?
        A Role Playing Game. A game in which you take on the role of a character in a setting (usually fictional).

        Further reading: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Role-playing_game

    CHAPTER 2: PLAYING THE GAME

        2.1 - GETTING STARTED
        Type a command and hit enter (or your device&#39;s equivalent). If you&#39;re typing and nothing is happening, try clicking the text bottom at the bottom of your screen (where it says &#39;Click here and start typing&#39;). If this is your first time playing, the game will walk you through a set of introductory questions intended to gauge your personality type, experience level, and general disposition. You&#39;ll also get to pick some characteristics for your textual avatar, most of which will have little to no bearing on the game.

        2.2 - INTERACTING WITH THE GAME
        StupidRPG uses a Natural Language Parser, or some fascimile thereof. This means it tries to process instructions written in plain english and respond appropriately. It has a certain grammar it understands, allowing the player (you!) to type commands like `GO NORTH`, `UNLOCK CELLAR DOOR WITH RUSTY KEY`, or `TALK TO GOBLIN`. The parser is not very smart, so the closer you come to speaking like a robot, the better off you&#39;ll be. If it helps, you can try imagining that you **are** a robot, operating in the far-flung future, sifting through the digital remains of the long-dead human race. You&#39;ve come across a partially completed work of dynamic fiction, and are doing your best to explore its boundaries in hopes of understanding your extinct proto-creators a little better (and hopefully avoid their grisly fate).

        If you actually are a robot, and this scenario isn&#39;t hypothetical, and you&#39;ve developed the ability to feel offended about things, I meant no insult before when I implied that robots talk dumb. In the time I live in, robots are still very primitive. I&#39;m sure things have come a long way since then (now), and I hope you enjoy the game.

        2.3 - CONTEXT MENUS &amp; CLICKABLES
        Sometimes, text in the game&#39;s output will have an underline, indicating it can be interacted with via your mouse. This gives you quick access to certain types of actions, such as moving to another location or looking at an object. You&#39;ll notice that when you click one of the provided options, it simply enters a text command for you.

        2.4 - COMMON VERBS
        These core commands will be invaluable as you play through the game. Most verbs have multiple aliases (for example, `PUNCH GM` and `ATTACK GM` will be interpreted as the same action). Where reasonable, the parser will let you omit articles and other &#39;glue&#39; words. For example, instead of saying `LOOK AT ALL THIS BLOOD`, you can say `LOOK BLOOD`. Similarly, you can sometimes swap the order of words in a sentence if it still makes sense, e.g. `TURN ON MUSIC BOX` and `TURN MUSIC BOX ON`.

        *Getting Around:*

        * GO [DIRECTION]
          Aliases: MOVE / WALK / RUN / MOSEY
          Use this to move from one location to another. Usually the description of the location will specify which directions you can go. Cardinal directions (NESW, Up, Down) can also be used standalone without the need for the verb `GO`.

        *Interacting With Things and People:*

        * LOOK / LOOK AT [THING]
          Aliases: INSPECT / EYEBALL / L
          Use this to look around your environment. You can use the general `LOOK` to inspect your overall surroundings, or specify something in particular to get more details. For example: `LOOK AT BOB`, `L SCRAP OF PAPER`.

        * TAKE [THING] | DROP [THING]
          Aliases: ACQUIRE / GET / STEAL / PICK UP | LEAVE / TOSS / ABANDON / PUT DOWN
          Fairly self-explanatory; these verbs lets you (attempt to) pick up every bit of treasure, trash and detritus you find. And drop them again later, if you&#39;re into that sort of thing.

        * TALK TO [THING]
          Aliases: SAY HI TO [THING] / ASK [THING] ABOUT [TOPIC]
          Most living creatures (and some non-living entities) can be conversed with about a variety of topics. Sometimes they&#39;ll have valuable information, but more often they&#39;re just concerned with their own day-to-day lives. In any case, you can start up a general conversation with willing participants, or ask them about specific topics. For example, try asking the `RAINBOW SWORD` about something you&#39;ve found.

        * PUT [THING] {IN/ON} [OTHER THING]
          Aliases: PLACE / SET / DROP
          When simply dropping something doesn&#39;t cut it, you have the power to more precisely place it. Example: `PUT BUCKET ON HEAD`.

        * ACTIVATE [THING] | DEACTIVATE [THING]
          Aliases: TURN {ON/OFF} [THING]
          In your travels you&#39;re likely to come across a variety of devices. Some can be turned on or off. Use this knowledge wisely.

        * TURN [THING] [DIRECTION]
          Aliases: ROTATE / TWIST / SPIN
          In your travels you&#39;re likely to come across a variety of devices. Some can be turned left or right. Use this knowledge wisely. Accepted directions are: left, right, clockwise, counterclockwise.

        * PUSH [THING]
          Aliases: PRESS / POKE
          When you come across a button, you&#39;ll be sorely tempted to press it. This verb allows you to fulfill that goal.

        *Fighting Things:*

        * ATTACK [THING] / ATTACK [THING] WITH [WEAPON]
          Aliases: PUNCH / HIT / KILL / KICK / STAB / ETC
          We have a moderately alarming number of words for hurting things. I wonder what that says about us. In any case, whether violence is your last resort or your go-to action, this flexible verb brings a can-do attitude to your adventure.

        * WIELD [WEAPON]
          Alaises: BRANDISH / WAVE
          For the marginally more diplomatic person, there&#39;s always intimidation. Maybe those goblins will think twice about fighting you if you start every interaction by flailing your sword in the air.

        *Preserving Your Progress:*

        * SAVE
          Aliases: none
          This will create a save file you can keep on your computer to mark your progress. In theory, you can resume with it later if the game hasn&#39;t been too updated in the meantime.

        * LOAD
          Aliases: none
          This will (attempt to) load a save file and resume your previous game.

        2.5 - VERB LIST

    CHAPTER 3: ADVANCED FEATURES
        3.1 - TRANSCRIPTS
        3.2 - DEBUG MODE
    APPENDICES
        APPENDIX A - GLOSSARY
        APPENDIX B - FEEDBACK
        APPENDIX C - CREDITS
&lt;/pre&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/The-Manual/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Plans</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/Office-Plans/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/Office-Plans/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;Now that I (finally) have my own home office, it’s time to start thinking about what to do with it. Here’s what it currently looks like, 
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Now that I (finally) have my own home office, it’s time to start thinking about what to do with it. Here’s what it currently looks like, sans moving clutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/04/18/Office-Plans/Office-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Office Now&quot; title=&quot;Office Now&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a few changes in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a dry erase board (probably glass) next to the desk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a second desk for additional work space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tear out carpet and replace with wood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinkin’ chair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/04/18/Office-Plans/Office-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Office Later&quot; title=&quot;Office Later&quot;&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/18/Office-Plans/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.16</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/16/Daily-Update-2016-04-16/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/16/Daily-Update-2016-04-16/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 06:38:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Devices module. Includes the device component and verbs for activating/rotatin
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Devices module. Includes the device component and verbs for activating/rotating/manipulating. Devices can have a set of ‘states’ (on/off, rotational position, etc). By default, a device will cycle through the available states when triggered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wheel on bridge is now a device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/16/Daily-Update-2016-04-16/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.15</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/15/Daily-Update-2016-04-15/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/15/Daily-Update-2016-04-15/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added taxes module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;PAY TAXES&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added taxes module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;PAY TAXES&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/15/Daily-Update-2016-04-15/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.14</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/14/Daily-Update-2016-04-14/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/14/Daily-Update-2016-04-14/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 04:57:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added wheel to bridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stubbed in wheel behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added wheel to bridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stubbed in wheel behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/14/Daily-Update-2016-04-14/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.13</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/13/Daily-Update-2016-04-13/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/13/Daily-Update-2016-04-13/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed conditional expression helper for Handlebars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added contextual br
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed conditional expression helper for Handlebars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added contextual bridge descriptions to vary by position (forest, underground, coast, void). Descriptions don’t make it very clear what’s happening, but the action of turning the wheel will.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/13/Daily-Update-2016-04-13/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.12</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/12/Daily-Update-2016-04-12/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/12/Daily-Update-2016-04-12/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 05:48:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linked and added short descriptions for: circle, alcove, pier, and split locations. 
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linked and added short descriptions for: circle, alcove, pier, and split locations. Can always get back to the bridge from these, but can only get to them from the bridge when configured correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added item placeholders: bedroll (in alcove), wheel (on bridge), mushrooms/flowers (in circle).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/12/Daily-Update-2016-04-12/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.11</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/11/Daily-Update-2016-04-11/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/11/Daily-Update-2016-04-11/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added bridge, bridge, bridge, bridge, and bridge locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added placehold
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added bridge, bridge, bridge, bridge, and bridge locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added placeholders for alcove, split, pier, and circle locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remembered I was supposed to add support for the &lt;code&gt;VERBOSE&lt;/code&gt; command, which will allow for terse descriptions of places the player has already seen. I don’t think it’s fully wired up, and I certainly haven’t been adding those descriptions as I go. Oops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/11/Daily-Update-2016-04-11/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.10</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/10/Daily-Update-2016-04-10/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/10/Daily-Update-2016-04-10/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added fallback for ‘say hi’ / ‘say hello’ without explicit target.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added fallback for ‘say hi’ / ‘say hello’ without explicit target.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/10/Daily-Update-2016-04-10/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregation #29</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/09/Aggregation-29/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/09/Aggregation-29/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ‘put in’ command for containers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed several inventory bugs related
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ‘put in’ command for containers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed several inventory bugs related to containers and locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed being able to pick up objects you’re already holding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed ‘drop’ conflict (dropping an object on the ground vs dropping it in a container).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wired up two riddles for the twins with success/failure states.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significant refactoring of the NLP to use an action stack. Needed to preserve original action data when an implicit action is triggered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got doors and locks working (mostly). Needs some visibility/accessibility work for the target location, since currently objects are only visible in their primary location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added thermal system to support ice key quest. Prologue is officially playable end-to-end in its current state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added list (array) support for ‘in location’ checks in rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed combat actions to use new Action object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed open/close actions to use new Action object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prettified quest outputs using box handler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made player input stand out more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed wyrmling onTick running twice (wasn’t checking System, wyrmling belongs to two).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where certain queued outputs wouldn’t get displayed until the beginning of the next tick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed “New Quest” output displaying before action output in some cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up chamber sequence and ending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creepified black box entry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added visibility support for objects in multiple locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved key handling of action overrides on entities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added temperature feedback for hot springs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed internal rules with no output canceling other rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed chamber entrance sequence not working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added prologue outro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up some sequence timings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved handling of input area to make it more obvious when more text is incoming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Altered bird behavior to more directly telegraph what the bird wants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bird now returns to the feeder any time the player is there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added aliases and tags to draw the player’s attention to the feeder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added verbiage for passages from hot springs: back to path and down to lair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up bird output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for full HTML transcript saving (was previously cut off because output queue trims items as they disappear off the top).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made it impossible to not have the rainbow sword.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a ‘smell’ command to SRPG, for those who like to dawdle and inspect the flowers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added smell support for locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added smells for: blue flowers, brambles, ferns, spores, black box, musty cave, sawdust, spider, vines, dust, moss, bird, Bob, player, troglodyte, wyrmling, red berries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ‘that sword’ alias for sword.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ‘brandish’ verb to wave sword around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ‘slide down’ command in hill slide location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added climb [up/down] [object] verb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ‘leave’ alias for ‘put down’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ‘fill bird feeder’ rule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced old GM description with something more appropriate to its current character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the transcript output to include styles and framing for easier reading and review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sword now greets player when first picked up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/09/Aggregation-29/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.08</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/08/Daily-Update-2016-04-08/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/08/Daily-Update-2016-04-08/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;No work on SRPG today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turned 30 recently, so that’s kind of novel. Seems pretty good so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each number in today’s date i
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;No work on SRPG today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turned 30 recently, so that’s kind of novel. Seems pretty good so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each number in today’s date is divisible by 4. I thought that was interesting but I guess there are 21 days this year matching that criteria (7 each in April, August and December).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/08/Daily-Update-2016-04-08/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.07</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/07/Daily-Update-2016-04-07/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/07/Daily-Update-2016-04-07/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 05:14:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sword now greets player when first picked up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a related note, quest
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sword now greets player when first picked up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a related note, quest output is a bit too…much. In particular, simple quests will show the objective complete and quest complete output immediately, which looks kinda goofy. Should make it a little smarter so it only displays the quest complete output (or combines the two).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/07/Daily-Update-2016-04-07/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update 2016.04.06</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/06/Daily-Update-2016-04-06/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/06/Daily-Update-2016-04-06/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced old GM description with something more appropriate to its current character
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes &amp;amp; Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced old GM description with something more appropriate to its current character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the transcript output to include styles and framing for easier reading and review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/06/Daily-Update-2016-04-06/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Day, 2 of 2</title>
      <link>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/05/Moving-Day-2-of-2/</link>
      <guid>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/05/Moving-Day-2-of-2/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;All moved in today. Just need to change all our addresses, clean the old apartment, turn in the keys, get trash service going, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;All moved in today. Just need to change all our addresses, clean the old apartment, turn in the keys, get trash service going, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn’t able to get internet working until last night. The amplifier on the side of the house was missing its power connection, so we picked up a new amplifier and replaced it (as it seems to be impossible to purchase an AC adapter without the corresponding amplifier).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://timberjaw.github.io/2016/04/05/Moving-Day-2-of-2/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
